Mitchell Stephens Papers
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- 2. Research Materials, 1936-2016; 2.; About 3.75 linear feet Boxes: 9 Folders: 179
  - Subseries 2.15: Additional Materials, 2015-2016; 2.15; Boxes: 1 Folders: 14
    - New Materials, 2015 - 2016 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - New Materials, 2015 - 2016 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - New Materials, 2015 - 2016 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - New Materials, 2015 - 2016 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - New Materials, 2015 - 2016 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - New Materials, 2015 - 2016 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - New Materials, 2015 - 2016 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Untitled Transcript(Possibly Voice of America Documentary), undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
- 3. Correspondence, 2013-2016; 3.; About .5 linear feet Boxes: 1 Folders: 6
  Series contains consists of correspondence between Mitchell Stephens and Richard Moulton, Anne T. Donaghy, and Quaker Hill Historical Society. Rick Moulton sent DVDs as well as a Flash Drive of Lowell Thomas Photos which have been copied and included in Series 6. Digital Materials.
  - From Anne Donaghy, 2015 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - From Historical Society of Quaker Hill and Pawling, 2016 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - From Jesse White (Secretery of State of Illinois, 2015 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - From Rick Moulton, 2013 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - From Rick Moulton, 2013 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - From Thomas and Donaghy, 2015 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- 4. Photographs, undated; 4.; About .1 linear feet Boxes: .2 Folders: 1
  Series contains large print photographs of Lowell Thomas.
  Original Order
  - Photographs, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
- 5. Maps, 2007-2017; 5.; About .5 linear feet Boxes: 1 Folders: 1
  Series contains maps of places Mitchell Stephens visited while conducting research. Maps are of: Skagway, Alaska; London; Cripple Creek and Victor, Colorado; Yukon, Canada. There are maps of the various gold mines in Colorado as well.
  - Maps, 2007 - 2017 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- 6. Digital Materials, 2009 - 2022; 6; 8 GB Folders: 3
  Series contains digital research materials and manuscripts created by Mitchell Stephens.
  Subject
  - Subseries 6.1: Manuscripts and Research Materials, 2009-2022; 6.1; 8 GB Folders: 3
    Series contains manuscript drafts of The Voice of America and articles Stephens wrote on Lowell Thomas and other topics such as journalism and fake news. Research materials include interviews with Anne Donaghy and saved copies of journal and newspaper articles regarding Lowell Thomas and the places and times associated with him. Many of these pieces were printed out and written on by Stephens and can be found in Series 2: Research Materials. Voice of America is a documentary Stephens wrote and was directed by Richard Moulton and came out in 2019.
    Folders are arranged alphabetically. Some of the folder time stamps changed during processing.
    - Essays, 2009 - 2022 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - The Voice of America Biography, 2013 - 2017 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Voice of America Documentary, 2015 - 2017 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 6.2: Lowell Thomas Photographs from Richard Moulton, 2014 - 2016; 6.2; 168 MB Folders: 1
    Richard Moulton originally mailed these photographs of Lowell Thomas as a USB to Mitchell Stephens. They have now been copied and saved on a hard drive. Photographs include lantern slides of Lowell Thomas in Arabia, Egypt, Italy, Palestine, and London.
    - LT Photos Small USB, 2019 (Box 15, Folder 8)